ZEKIYE HALE COSAR

halealtunakar2@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/halealtunakar/ • https://github.com/halecosar • Istanbul, Turkey

·+534 693 5646

Software Developer | Bootcamp Assistant |

I made an exciting transition from working as a Human Resources specialist to embarking on a career in software development. Currently, I have completed a six-month Full Stack Development course at Patika. Dev, where I dedicated myself to improving my skills in Java and React.js. Focusing on the world of software, I worked on projects and enhanced my abilities. My career background, with a human-centric approach, now motivates me to create solutions through code.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Java, Spring Boot, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Postman

Key Achievements & Projects

I have successfully completed six graduation projects, with three focusing on backend development and two on frontend development. And a full-stack capstone project.

For my backend projects:

- My initial project involved learning the fundamentals of object-oriented programming with Java and developing the Minesweeper Game.
- The second project I designed utilized Java and Swing UI, and it was a Travel Agency application.
- Finally, I completed the Veterinary Management System application using Spring Boot and REST API.

Regarding my frontend projects:

- My first project was a Sports Center application developed using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- My final project, developed using React.js, was a quiz application.

As a capstone project, I also developed the client-side of the Veterinary Management System using React.js. Additionally, I utilized PostgreSQL for the database, integrated the frontend with React, designed the user interface using Material-UI, and managed forms with Formik.

EDUCATION

Istanbul University Management Information Systems 2023-Current.

Marmara University Political Science and Public Administration (French) 2015-2021

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Patika.Dev, Remote Mar 2024 - Current Patika + Bootcamp Assistant

- Following my graduation, I joined Patika as an educational assistant to provide support to upcoming software students.
- After completing my graduation, I transitioned into the role of an educational assistant at Patika, where I provide technical support to aspiring software students. Concurrently, as an education assistant in a Java Spring Boot bootcamp, where I offer specialized guidance and assistance to students navigating the intricacies of Java and Spring Boot development.

EARLIER WORK EXPERIENCE (Before my career change)

Recruiter / NBS Human Resources, Istanbul May 2023 - Aug 2023

• Interview and assessment skills, candidate tracking, creating recruitment strategies, keeping up with business trends, and communication skills.

People & Culture Specialist / Paynet Payment Services, Istanbul Feb 2022 – May-2023

- •Employee relations, conflict resolution skills, cultural analysis, leadership development, diversity and inclusion strategies, creating training and development programs, emotional intelligence, and communication skills.
- While working at this company, the internal human resources application had just started to be used. I played a role in its testing and collaborated closely with the IT teams.

LANGUAGES

Professional Proficiency in English and French.

TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS

Patika.Dev , Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp / Certificate, 2024